Guide to the Alexander Mordecai Bickel Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- LEGAL PRACTICE, 1950, 1954, 1967-1974; Series X; 7 linear feet (16 boxes)
  - Spangler v. Pasadena City Board of Education
    - U. S. District Court:
      - notice of motion and motion by defendants for (1) relief from the Court's judgement, (2) dissolution of the Court's injunction, (3) termination of the Court's continuing supervision … and (4) alternatively, for modification of plan for integration dated February 18, 1970, and memorandum of points and authorities in support thereof, 1973 December 19 (Box 52, Folder 108)
      - supporting affidavits, 1973 December 19 (Box 52, Folder 108)
      - preliminary response of plaintiff-intervenor, the United States, and memorandum of points and authorities in support thereof, 1974 January 22 (Box 52, Folder 108)
      - memorandum of points and authorities in opposition to motion of Pia Smith, Nora Jean Lester, and the NAACP to intervene as plaintiffs, 1974 February 4 (Box 52, Folder 108)
    - Paul, Hastings, Janofsky & Walker, attorneys for the defendants:
      - trial brief, first draft, 1974 February 15, 18 (Box 52, Folder 109)
    - U. S. District Court:
      - reporter's transcript of proceedings, 1974 February 25 (Box 52, Folder 110)
      - reporter's transcript of proceedings, 1974 February 26, 28, March 1 (Box 53, Folder 111-113)
      - trial stipulation, 1974 February 23 (Box 53, Folder 114)
      - plaintiff-intervenor's proposed findings of fact and conclusions of law, 1974 March 14 (Box 53, Folder 114)
      - proposed order, 1974 March 12 (Box 53, Folder 114)
      - objections to findings of fact and conclusions of law proposed by plaintiff-intervenor and supplemental findings of fact and conclusions of law proposed by defendants, 1974 March 18 (Box 53, Folder 114)
    - Correspondence, 1974 March 18-May 7 (Box 53, Folder 115)
    - U. S. District Court: opinion and order, 1974 May 3 (Box 53, Folder 115)
    - Correspondence, 1974 May 14-October 14 (Box 53, Folder 115)
    - U. S. Court of Appeals:
      - defendants-appellants' opening brief, 1974 August 19 (Box 53, Folder 115)
      - defendants-appellants' reply brief, 1974 October 3 (Box 53, Folder 115)
    - Henry Marcheschi:
      - "The New Pasadena Plan: A Recommended New Approach to Achieve Voluntary Integration and Equality of Educational Opportunity…: part II - The Plan and Its Implementation", 1971 November 9 (Box 53, Folder 116)
      - "The New Pasadena Plan …: Part III - Reprise", 1971 December 21 (Box 53, Folder 116)
      - A True Alternative to Segregation -- A. Proposal for Community School Districts: Preliminary Proposal, 1972 May 3 (Box 53, Folder 116)
  - Swann v. Charlotte-Mecklenburg
    - CORE:
      - Memoranda to Floyd Abrams, "NBC -- Matter of Pappas", 1970 February (Box 53, Folder 117)
      - press releases, 1970 February-March (Box 53, Folder 117)
    - U. S. Supreme Court: motion for leave to file brief amicus curiae in support of petition for writ of certiorari and brief amicus curiae for National Education Association, 1970 June 25 (Box 53, Folder 117)
    - Roy Innis, National Director, CORE: correspondence, 1970 August 21-September 1 (Box 53, Folder 118)
    - A. Bickel: "Outline and Prospectus" of motion for leave to file brief amicus curiae and brief amicus curiae for CORE, 1970 August 31 (Box 53, Folder 118)
    - Henry Marcheschi: letter to Roy Innis, 1970 September 16 (Box 53, Folder 118)
    - U. S. Supreme Court:
      - motion for leave to file brief amicus curiae and brief amicus curiae for CORE, 1970 October 12 (Box 53, Folder 119)
      - opinion, 1971 April 21 (Box 53, Folder 119)
  - U. S. v. Caldwell
    - U. S. Court of Appeals:
      - brief for appellant Earl Caldwell, 1970 post-June 30 (Box 53, Folder 120)
      - brief of the American Civil Liberties Union … and a group of reporters, writers, and editors, amici curiae, 1970 July 20 (Box 54, Folder 121)
      - brief for the United States, 1970 August 6 (Box 54, Folder 121)
      - reply brief for appellant, 1970 August 11 (Box 54, Folder 121)
      - brief of Authors League of America as amicus curiae, 1970 (Box 54, Folder 121)
      - brief of New York Times Company as amicus curiae, 1970 (Box 54, Folder 121)
    - James C. Goodale, vice president and general counsel, New York Times: correspondence, 1971 May 26-1972 January 27 (Box 54, Folder 122)
    - Floyd Abrams, attorney for NBC: correspondence, 1971 May 27-1972 January 27 (Box 54, Folder 123)
    - Memoranda to Floyd Abrams, "NBC - General", 1970 February 24, March 30 (Box 54, Folder 124)
    - Memorandum to Floyd Abrams, "NBC -- Matter of Pappas", 1971 June 2-July l6 (Box 54, Folder 125)
    - Draft outline -- monetary report, 1971 August 2 (Box 54, Folder 126)
    - Pillsbury, Madison & Sutro, attorneys for the New York Times:
      - letters, 1971 June 2-July 26 (Box 54, Folder 127)
      - memorandum, "Assertion of Privilege In Camera: Review and Disclosure Requirements", 1971 July 16 (Box 54, Folder 127)
    - Paul Nejelski, Institute of Judicial Administration: memorandum, "Filing an amicus brief in Caldwell on behalf of the criminal justice research community", [1971 July 26?] (Box 54, Folder 128)
    - U. S. Supreme Court: correspondence, 1971 August 2-October 12 (Box 54, Folder 128)
    - Larry Scharff, attorney for Radio Television News Directors Association: letter, 1971 August 3 (Box 54, Folder 128)
    - A. Bickel:
      - "First Outline of Argument", 1971 June 1 (Box 54, Folder 129)
      - brief of the New York Times Co., etc., as amici curiae, first draft, statement and argument, 1971 June 22 (Box 54, Folder 129)
      - brief of the New York Times Co., etc., as amici curiae, second draft, 1971 August 10 (Box 54, Folder 130)
      - brief of the New York Times Co., etc., as amici curiae, final draft, 1971 September 8 (Box 54, Folder 131)
      - memoranda, 1971 May 28, August 2 (Box 54, Folder 132)
      - notes, undated (Box 54, Folder 132)
    - E. Barrett Prettyman, Jr., attorney for Paul Pappas: correspondence, 1971 August 10-September 28 (Box 54, Folder 133)
    - Alan J. Hruska, attorney for CBS: correspondence, 1971 September 1-7 (Box 54, Folder 133)
    - Leo P. Larkin, Jr., attorney for the Washington Post and Newsweek: letter, 1971 September 17 (Box 54, Folder 133)
    - U. S. Supreme Court:
      - brief for the United States, petitioner, 1971 July (Box 54, Folder 134)
      - brief for respondent, Earl Caldwell, 1971 October term (Box 54, Folder 134)
      - brief of the New York Times Co. … as amici curiae, 1971 post-September 8 (Box 55, Folder 135)
      - brief of the Washington Post Co. and Newsweek as amici curiae in support of respondent, 1971 September 17 (Box 55, Folder 136)
      - brief for Radio Television News Directors Association as amicus curiae, 1971 September (Box 55, Folder 137)
      - brief for Chicago Tribune Co. as amicus curiae, 1971 September (Box 55, Folder 137)
      - reply brief for the United States, 1972 February (Box 55, Folder 137)
    - U. S. Supreme Court (Branzburg):
      - brief for petitioner, Paul M. Branzburg, 1971 July 15 (Box 55, Folder 138)
      - brief for the United States as amicus curiae, 1971 September (Box 55, Folder 138)
      - reply brief for petitioner, 1971 October term (Box 55, Folder 138)
    - U. S. Supreme Court (Pappas): brief for petitioner, 1971 October term (Box 55, Folder 138)
    - Federal Trade Commission (in the matter of the Hearst Corporation):
      - motion to quash subpoena of Arthur E. Rowse, 1971 August 26 (Box 55, Folder 139)
      - memorandum of law in support of motion to quash subpoena, 1971 August 26 (Box 55, Folder 139)
      - affidavit of Arthur E. Rowse, 1971 August 27 (Box 55, Folder 139)
    - Alexander Greenfeld, legal department, New York Times: papers relating to the Popkin case, 1972 December 7-1973 January 4 (Box 55, Folder 140)
    - Clippings, 1970-1972, undated (Box 55, Folder 141)
    - Editorial riders, undated (Box 55, Folder 142)
    - Lists of interested parties, undated (Box 55, Folder 142)
  - U. S. v. Coffin et al.
    - William S. Coffin: speeches and statements, 1967 (Box 55, Folder 143)
    - Writings on resistance, 1967, undated (Box 55, Folder 143)
    - Yale University faculty: advertisement, Yale Daily News, 1968 February 23 (Box 55, Folder 143)
    - A. Bickel: memorandum, "The First Amendment Issue", 1968 February 2 (Box 55, Folder 144)
    - John Griffiths: critique of "The First Amendment Issue", 1968 February 12 (Box 55, Folder 144)
    - Alex Capron: memorandum, 1968 February 20 (Box 55, Folder 144)
    - A. Bickel:
      - "Comments on Government's Memorandum in Opposition to Defendant's Motion to Dismiss the Indictment in United States v. Coffin ", 1968 April 1 (Box 55, Folder 144)
      - memorandum, "Problems of Proof: First Amendment Issues", 1968 May 10 (Box 55, Folder 144)
      - memorandum, "Coffin Case", 1968 June 9 (Box 55, Folder 144)
    - U. S. District Court:
      - indictment, 1968 January 5 (Box 55, Folder 145)
      - government's memorandum in opposition to defendants' motions to dismiss the indictment, 1968 pre-April 1 (Box 55, Folder 145)
    - U. S. Court of Appeals: opinion, 1969 July 11 (Box 55, Folder 145)
  - U. S. v. Indianapolis School Board
    - U. S. District Court:
      - memorandum of decision, 1971 August 18 (Box 55, Folder 146)
      - trial brief of the Metropolitan School Districts of Lawrence, Warren, and Wayne Town-ships, Marion County, Indiana, 1973 pre-June 21 (Box 55, Folder 147)
      - transcript of proceedings on trial, Vol. VII, pp. 1299-1394, 1973 June 21 (Box 55, Folder 148)
      - transcript of proceedings on trial, Vol. XV, pp. 2650-2842, 1973 July 6 (Box 56, Folder 149)
      - amicus brief of Coalition for Integrated Education, 1973 July 11 (Box 56, Folder 150)
      - brief for added defendant the Metropolitan School District of Perry Township answering brief submitted by amicus curiae, 1973 July 17 (Box 56, Folder 150)
      - answer brief of certain defendants to brief of amicus curiae, 1973 July 18 (Box 56, Folder 150)
      - memorandum of decision, 1973 July 20 (Box 56, Folder 151)
      - notice of appeal, 1973 July 30 (Box 56, Folder 151)
      - motion of added defendants for stay of order entered July 20, 1973, pending appeal, 1973 post-July 20 (Box 56, Folder 151)
      - affidavits supporting motion of added defendants for stay of order pending appeal, 1973 July 26-31 (Box 56, Folder 152)
    - Correspondence, 1972, 1973 July 31-August 2 (Box 56, Folder 153)
    - U. S. Court of Appeals, Seventh Circuit:
      - defendants-appellants' motion for stay of orders of U. S. District Court entered July 20, 1973, pending appeal, 1973 August 1 (Box 56, Folder 153)
      - request for oral argument on motion for stay and motion for consolidation of proceedings with respect to application for stay, 1973 August 1 (Box 56, Folder 153)
    - Correspondence, 1973 August 2-30 (Box 56, Folder 153)
    - Lewis C. Bose, attorney for added defendants: memorandum, "Suggested Legislation: Desegregation Situations", 1973 August 16 (Box 56, Folder 153)
    - U. S. District Court:
      - additional authorities in support of motion for stay of order entered July 20, 1973, pending appeal, 1973 August 7 (Box 56, Folder 154)
      - motion for modification of decree for interim relief by added defendant Mooresfield Consolidated School Corporation, [1973 Aug?] (Box 56, Folder 154)
    - Correspondence, 1973 September 4-22 (Box 56, Folder 155)
    - Donald P. Bogard, Deputy Attorney General, Indiana:
      - draft motion for stay of appellate proceedings and an enlargement of time, 1973 pre-September 22 (Box 56, Folder 155)
      - draft brief in support of motion, 1973 pre-September 22 (Box 56, Folder 155)
    - A. Bickel: comment on motion and brief, 1973 September 29 (Box 56, Folder 155)
    - U. S. Court of Appeals, Seventh Circuit:
      - brief for appellants, [1973?] (Box 56, Folder 156)
      - appendix, [1973?] (Box 56, Folder 156)
      - book of exhibits, [1973?] (Box 56, Folder 157)
      - motion for temporary stay of appellate proceedings and an enlargement of time, 1973 October 22 (Box 56, Folder 158)
      - brief in support of motion, 1973 October 22 (Box 56, Folder 158)
      - response of the United States to motion, 1973 November 2 (Box 56, Folder 158)
      - motion of the United States for injunction pending appeal, 1973 November 5 (Box 56, Folder 158)
    - U. S. Supreme Court, docket nos. 73-434 to 73-436 (Milliken v. Bradley):
      - petition for writ of certiorari to the U. S. Court of Appeals, Sixth Circuit, 1973 August 6, September 6 (Box 56, Folder 159)
      - memorandum in opposition to petitions for writs of certiorari, 1973 October term (Box 56, Folder 159)
      - brief on the merits in support of petitioners submitted amicus curiae by the state of Indiana, 1973 October term (Box 56, Folder 159)
    - U. S. District Court, Western District of Michigan (Higgins v. Board of Education of Grand Rapids): opinion, 1973 July 18 (Box 56, Folder 160)
  - Villanova University
    - A. Bickel:
      - notes, 1954 post-August 21 (Box 58, Folder 177)
      - memorandum, 1954 September 7 (Box 58, Folder 177)
  - Watergate
    - U. S. District Court (in re subpoena issued to Richard M. Nixon):
      - brief in opposition, 1973 August 7 (Box 58, Folder 178)
      - reply brief, 1973 August 17 (Box 58, Folder 178)
    - U. S. District Court ( Nader v. Butz ): memorandum of law in support of motion to remand or in the alternative to supplement the record, 1973 September 14 (Box 58, Folder 179)
    - U. S. District Court ( Nixon v. Sirica, U. S. v. Sirica ): reply brief of Richard M. Nixon, 1973 September 19 (Box 58, Folder 179)
    - U. S. District Court ( Senate Select Committee v. Nixon ): brief of Richard M. Nixon in opposition to plaintiffs' motion for summary judgment, 1973 September 24 (Box 58, Folder 180)
    - Charles H. Percy: staff memorandum, "Constitutional background for limiting the dismissal power of the President", 1973 October 31 (Box 58, Folder 181)
    - Clippings, 1973 (Box 58, Folder 181)
    - Watergate Special Prosecution Force: correspondence, 1974 May 24-July 3 (Box 58, Folder 181)
  - Williams v. U. S.
    - U. S. Supreme Court:
      - petition for writ of certiorari, 1971 post-November 4 (Box 58, Folder 182)
      - brief for the United States, 1972 January (Box 58, Folder 182)
- TEACHING, 1956-1975; Series XI; 5.5 linear feet (15 boxes)
  Series XI, TEACHING, consists of correspondence, examinations, lectures, teaching material, and faculty and committee memoranda arranged in four sections: Yale Law School, Yale University, DeVane Lectures, and Other Institutions. The major items connected with Bickel's own teaching are these: his manual, "Constitutional Law," for the Clark-Whitman Bar Review Course; printed matter compiled for his courses in Yale Law School; and texts of his DeVane Lectures, delivered in Yale College in 1972 and 1973, The second set of DeVane Lectures was a major source for The Morality of Consent (Series II).
  The principal items unconnected with his own teaching relate to policy development in the university and the law school. Between 1967 and 1970 Bickel served on several university committees: the Advisory Committee on Education, the Committee on Disciplinary Policy, the Faculty Advisory Committee on the Colleges. There are letters, memoranda, and reports documenting the work of these bodies, but it is not evident that Bickel played a major role. Among the law school papers, the outstanding items are Bickel's memoranda on curriculum and discipline, written in 1968 and 1969 to counter laxity in faculty opinion. Most of the other papers in this series deal with routine business of institutional management and alumni relations. Bickel's correspondence with presidents of the university, deans of the law school, and many other Yale professors and administrators is in Series I.
  TEACHING has four sections: Yale Law School, Yale University, DeVane Lectures, and Other Institutions. Devane Lectures is in chronological order. The other sections are in alphabetical order.
  - Yale Law School
    - [Administrative Law course?]: Jaffe and Nathanson, Administrative Law and Supplement (annotated and interleaved), [post-1968, post-1972] (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Administrative Process course: exams, 1957-1973 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - "Advisory Opinions": research assistant's notes
      - General, undated (Box 59, Folder 3)
      - Foreign, undated (Box 59, Folder 4)
      - Alabama-Florida, undated (Box 59, Folder 5)
      - Hawaii-Vermont, undated (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Alumni Association: correspondence, 1957-1971 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - Assignment book and class lists, 1960-1961 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Assignment book, 1961-1962 (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Bickel, A.: "Memorandum to the Faculty" on curriculum, 1968 November 6 (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Bickel, A., et al.: memorandum to the faculty on discipline, 1969 November-December (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Bittker-Clark Bar Review Course (Tape of Lecture), 1968 June (Box 60, Folder 10a.)
    - Black Panther Trial Report Committee: memorandum, 1970 April 29 (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Class schedules and course lists, 1956-1967 (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Constitutional Law course
      - Teaching material, 1957 undated (Box 60, Folder 13)
      - Exams, 1957-1972 (Box 60, Folder 14)
      - Teaching material, 1968 (Box 60, Folder 15)
      - List of cases, 1968 (Box 61, Folder 16)
      - Teaching material, undated (Box 61, Folder 16)
      - Teaching material, undated (Box 61, Folder 17-19)
      - Gunther and Dowling, Constitutional Law, 8th ed. (annotated and interleaved), undated (Box 62, Folder 20)
    - Curriculum Committee: reports and memoranda, 1955-1957 (Box 63, Folder 21)
    - Disciplinary Panel: report and memoranda, 1969 October-December (Box 63, Folder 22)
    - Disciplinary Policy, Committee on
      - "Report", 1970 April 29 (Box 63, Folder 22)
      - "Code of Rights and Duties", 1970 post-May 11 (Box 63, Folder 22)
    - Faculty:, minutes of meetings (Box 63, Folder 23)
    - Faculty: miscellaneous reports and memoranda, 1956-1964, undated (Box 63, Folder 23)
    - File headings, 1967, undated (Box 63, Folder 24)
    - "Government Regulation": notes, undated (Box 63, Folder 25)
    - Grading Committee: memoranda and correspondence, 1968 February-June (Box 63, Folder 26)
    - Intensive Semester Program: letters from Dan Freed, 1971 (Box 63, Folder 27)
    - Law and the Problem of Industrial Concentration course: notes, undated (Box 63, Folder 27)
    - Library: correspondence and memoranda, 1964-1974 (Box 64, Folder 28)
    - Library: miscellaneous correspondence, 1960-1970 (Box 64, Folder 28)
    - Public Law course: exams, 1956-1959 (Box 64, Folder 28)
    - Public Schools course
      - "Table of Contents for Seminar Materials", 1966-1967 (Box 64, Folder 29)
      - Teaching material, Part III, 1968 (Box 64, Folder 30)
      - Teaching material, Part IV, 1968 (Box 64, Folder 31)
      - Teaching material, 1969-1970 (Box 64, Folder 32-33)
      - Teaching material, 1969-1970 (Box 65, Folder 34-35)
      - Teaching material, 1969-1970, undated (Box 66, Folder 36-38)
      - Teaching material, Part V, pp. 980-1120, 1969-1970 (Box 67, Folder 39)
      - Teaching material, Part V, pp. 1121-1302, 1969-1970 (Box 67, Folder 40)
      - Teaching material, Part V, pp. 1303-1480, 1969-1970 (Box 67, Folder 41)
      - Teaching material, Part V, supplements 1 and 2, 1969-1970 (Box 67, Folder 42)
      - Teaching material, Part VI, pp, 1904-2085, 1969-1970 (Box 67, Folder 43)
      - Teaching material, Part VI, pp. 2086-2166, 1969-1970 (Box 67, Folder 44)
      - Teaching material, Parts V-VI, supplement, draft and revised draft, 1970 (Box 67, Folder 45)
      - Teaching material, undated (Box 68, Folder 46-47)
      - Teaching material, pp. 1-200, undated (Box 68, Folder 48)
      - Teaching material, pp. 201-371B, undated (Box 68, Folder 49)
      - Teaching material, undated (Box 68, Folder 50)
      - Printed matter, undated (Box 69, Folder 51)
    - Race Relations Law course
      - Teaching material, pp. 394-604, 1965 (Box 69, Folder 52)
      - Teaching material, pp. 605-765, 1965 (Box 69, Folder 53)
    - Student Association, Academic Committee: "A Vigorous and Fruitful Tree" (first annual report), 1967 May (Box 70, Folder 54)
    - Teaching materials, undated (Box 70, Folder 55)
  - Yale University
    - Alumni Communications and Public Information: correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 70, Folder 56)
    - Alumni Fund: correspondence, 1971 (Box 70, Folder 56)
    - Club: correspondence, 1969, 1973 (Box 70, Folder 56)
    - College, Dean's Office: letter, 1968 (Box 70, Folder 56)
    - Colleges, President's Committee on: reports, memoranda, and correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 70, Folder 57)
    - Disciplinary Policy, Committee on
      - Reports, memoranda, and letters, 1968 December-1970 Oct, undated (Box 70, Folder 58-59)
    - Education, Advisory Committee on: memoranda, 1969 October-November (Box 70, Folder 60)
    - History department: correspondence, 1963-1968 (Box 70, Folder 61)
    - Jewish Appeal: correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 70, Folder 61)
    - Library: correspondence, 1963-1973 (Box 70, Folder 61)
    - Midwestern Office: correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 70, Folder 61)
    - Press: correspondence, 1962-1974 (Box 70, Folder 62)
    - ROTC: correspondence, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 62)
    - Research and Development, University Library, Faculty Advisory Committee for
      - Reports and memoranda, 1967 May-July (Box 70, Folder 63)
      - Memoranda, 1967 August-Oct, 1968 March-April (Box 70, Folder 64)
      - Reports and memorandum, 1968 May (Box 70, Folder 65)
      - Reports, 1968 November-1969 January (Box 70, Folder 66)
    - Secretary: correspondence and M.A. diploma, 1960-1974 (Box 70, Folder 67)
    - Western Office: correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 70, Folder 67)
  - DeVane Lectures
    - Correspondence, 1970 December-1972 February (Box 70, Folder 68)
    - Source materials, undated (Box 70, Folder 68)
    - Research paper on the concept of citizenship, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 69)
    - Reading list and final exam, 1972 Jan, May (Box 71, Folder 70)
    - Text no. 1, draft and transcript, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 70)
    - Text no. 2, draft and transcript, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 71)
    - Text no. 3, draft and transcript, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 72)
    - Text no. 4, draft and transcript, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 73)
    - Text no. 5, draft and transcript, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 74)
    - Text no. 6, draft and transcript, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 75)
    - Text no. 7, draft and transcript, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 76)
    - Text no. 8, draft, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 77)
    - Text no. 9, draft and transcript, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 78)
    - Text no. 10, draft and transcript, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 79)
    - Text no. 11, draft and transcript, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 80)
    - Text no. 12, draft and transcript, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 81)
    - Text no. 13, draft, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 82)
    - Administrative and research material, 1973 (Box 71, Folder 83)
    - Syllabus and teaching material, undated (Box 71, Folder 84)
    - "Introduction and Citizenship", 1973 January 23 (Box 72, Folder 85)
    - "Citizenship (cont'd)", 1973 January 30 (Box 72, Folder 86)
    - "The Duty to Obey:, Conscientious Objection" (Box 72, Folder 87)
    - "The Duty to Obey: Civil Disobedience", 1973 February 13 (Box 72, Folder 88)
    - "The First Amendment", 1973 February 20 (Box 72, Folder 89)
    - "The First Amendment", 1973 February 27 (Box 72, Folder 90)
    - "The Duty to Obey: Civil Disobedience and Its Limits", 1973 March 6 (Box 72, Folder 91)